人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：天朝直属  面条打包子  乖宝宝运气好
翻译：NoNopig  油炸电风扇  somehacker
时间轴：Sage  泥球球   特效&压制：灰灰是菇凉
翻译&校对&总监：阿好
你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来
if your number's up,
我们就会找到你
we'll find you.
第二季 第二十集
疑犯追踪
我认为我们要对付的是一帮腐败警察
I think we're up against a group of corrupt cops.
音频拦截
会话分析
语言识别
他们偷走毒品  现金
They steal the drugs, the cash,
把目击者全杀了
and they kill all the witnesses.
斯蒂尔斯是缉毒组的
Stills is Narcotics.
是  我知道斯蒂尔斯警探的事
Yeah, I know damn well what happened to Detective Stills,
音频拦截
会话分析
语言识别
还有弗斯科警探的事
and so does Detective Fusco.
你想知道什么  我都告诉你
I'll tell you everything you want to know.
我们的新号码今天要去领奖  芬奇
Our new number is receiving an award today, Finch.
布克尔大学
经过了三十载的教学和批判研究
Three decades of teaching and critical research,
首席心脏外科手术专家
chief of Cardiac Surgery,
心脏移植领域的领袖
a leader in the field of heart transplants,
非体外循环心血管旁路手术的先驱
a pioneer in off-pump bypass cardiovascular surgery.
数百名病人的心脏和性命
He has held the hearts and lives of hundreds of patients
被他拯救
in his hands.
今天  我们非常荣幸地授予理查德・尼尔森医生
And today we are proud to bestow upon Dr. Richard Nelson
荣誉教授称号
the title of Professor Emeritus.
听起来这位新号码
Sounds like our latest number
脑容量跟你一样大啊  芬奇
has a brain almost as big as yours, Finch.
要是我再有双外科医生的手就好了
If only mine were attached to a surgeon's hands.
医生  科学家  教师
Doctor, scientist, teacher,
深受同行尊重
admired by his peers.
看来可不像是行凶者
Seems unlikely he's a perpetrator.
所以我怀疑凶手是不是正混迹在人群中
Which makes me wonder if his killer could be in this crowd.
理查德・尼尔森
强制配对
完成
感谢迪・马特奥医生的溢美之词
Thank you, Dr. Di Matteo, for those kind words.
你没提"零差点高尔夫球手"
You left out scratch golfer.
我记得柏拉图曾经说过
I think it was Plato that said knowledge
知识是灵魂的食粮
is the food of the soul.
在这些艰难的时刻
In these trying times,
我们应该记住柏拉图的话
we should heed the words of Plato,
"制造冤屈之人
"He who commits injustice
比遭受冤屈之人更可怜"
is ever made more wretched than he who suffers it."
这种冤屈永远无法削弱
This injustice will never diminish
正直者的生命及善行
the life and actions of a good man.
我的教子  卡尔文・比彻
My godson, Calvin Beecher.
一生勇毅
Brave to the end.
愿他安息
May he rest in peace.
举枪致敬
Present arms!
准备
Ready!
鸣枪
Fire!
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you very much.
感谢前来
Thank you for coming.
谢谢
Thank you.
接下来有什么打算  尼尔森医生
So, what's next, Dr. Nelson?
我需要换新心脏医生吗
Do I need a new cardiologist?
布兰登  你来做什么
Brandon, what are you doing here?
拜托  难得自己的医生获此殊荣
Come on, it's not often your doctor gets emeritus.
你实至名归
You deserved it.
谢了  不过我还不会走人
Thanks, but I'm not going anywhere just yet.
尼尔森有个病人来了  芬奇
One of Nelson's patients is here, Finch.
布兰登・博伊德  VAC资本操盘手
Brandon Boyd, a trader at VAC Capital,
是家著名的对冲基金
a prominent hedge fund.
高收入客户的资产经理
Asset management for high-income clients.
我猜我得多上点心关注
I guess I'm gonna have to start giving more attention
我的退休投资组合了
to my retirement portfolio, huh?
周四来场壁球
Racquetball Thursday?
你跟我重赛  我跟你讨教一下
You give me a rematch, I'll pick your brain
医疗产业新兴市场的情况
about some emerging markets in the health care industry.
周四俱乐部  不见不散
Thursday at the club, you're on.
-好  -谢了
- All right. - Thanks.
别急  医生
Not so fast, Doc.
想要灌倒你的肚子
If you're gonna rot your gut,
也得优雅点  是吧
you might as well do it in style, right?
62年的
'62?
罗斯莫医生  你从哪里搞来如此美酒
Dr. Rossmore, where did you locate such a magical elixir?
我有个病人  有家大型的酒厂
I have a patient who owns a very large distillery,
他的新心脏是你给做的
and he has a new heart that came from you.
格瑞特
Listen, Garrett...
关于菲利亚药品试验
about the Philia drug trial,
我很抱歉委员会建议
I'm really sorry about the board's recommendation--
没什么  跟你和委员会都没关系
Nonsense. It had nothing to do with the board or with you.
我们不够数据来支撑
We didn't have the data to support it.
格瑞特・罗斯莫医生
Dr. Garrett Rossmore,
值得尊敬的同僚  研究科学家
esteemed colleague and research scientist.
现在为菲利亚制药工作
He now works for Philia Pharmaceuticals.
大制药厂  他是做药的
Big pharma, he's a drug guy.
罗斯莫研发了一种新抑制素来提高高密度脂蛋白
Rossmore developed a new statin to raise HDL
降低胆固醇
and combat cholesterol.
新药走到了第三阶段的试验
Made it all the way to phase three in trials,
结果表现不佳
until it underperformed.
尼尔森医生是独立审查委员会的成员之一
Dr. Nelson was a member of the independent review board
该委员会叫停了这项试验
that halted the trials.
本可一鸣惊人的药品现在血本无归
Potential blockbuster drug down the drain.
似乎让菲利亚赔了数亿
Likely cost Philia billions in lost revenues,
更别提罗斯莫浪费了六年来研究
not to mention six years of Rossmore's research.
真惨
That had to hurt.
我知道你跟这事儿有关
I know you had a hand in this.
我知道你是比彻被杀的背后主使
I know you were behind Beecher's murder.
你别想逍遥法外
You're not gonna get away with this.
告诉我  弗斯科  为什么你身边的人
Tell me, Fusco, how is it everybody around you
都死于非命呢
winds up getting killed?
有点可疑了哦
Starting to look suspicious.
你会付出代价的  我会扳倒你
You're gonna pay for this. I'm gonna take you down.
你有个坏毛病
You got a bad habit of
总是忘记谁才是你的朋友
forgetting who your friends are.
你那些老朋友要么被抓  要么失踪
Of all your old pals who got locked up or went missing,
只有你逍遥在外
and you're the only one who got to walk away?
你还真以为是因为自己聪明吗
Did you honestly think that was because you were so smart?
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
保护伞
Protection.
你已经失去了
The kind you don't have anymore.
我听到风声
See, I hear things.
内务部  正在查你的老朋友阿扎雷洛
IAB, they're looking at your old pal Azarello
关于十几起谋杀案的事
on at least a dozen old murder counts.
肯定会很有趣
That should be interesting.
过去总是会阴魂不散
Past has a way of coming back to haunt you.
等我们搞完之后  莱奈尔
And by the time I'm done with you, Lionel,
你肯定恨不得跟比彻一起下葬
you're gonna wish you were in the ground with Beecher.
恭喜您  医生
Congratulations, Doctor.
很高兴看到有人的工作能被认可
It's nice to see someone being recognized for their body of work.
希望我也有这一天
I should be so lucky one day.
副教授朱莉安娜・迪・马特奥医生
Associate professor Dr. Juliana Di Matteo.
以前是尼尔森的助教和学生
Came up as Nelson's research assistant and protege.
可还没当上终身教授
But still hasn't made tenure.
-见过我女儿了吗  -我想她先看到我了
- Have you seen my daughter? - I think she saw me first.
所以才提前走了
Probably why she left so early.
理查德  你还好吗
Richard, are you okay?
你鼻子流血了
Your nose is bleeding.
天啊  我得拿点东西
Oh, gosh, I'm gonna go get something.
谢谢
Thank you.
-给  -谢谢
- Here you are. - Thank you.
尼尔森有个女儿  芬奇
Nelson has a daughter here, Finch.
莫莉・尼尔森  大三学生
Molly Nelson, registered as a junior
但被留校察看一学期
but suspended for a semester
因其在一次校园游行中袭击了一名警察
after assaulting a police officer during a campus demonstration.
-需要帮助吗  先生  -我有点头晕
- You need some help, Sir? - I feel a little light-headed.
-坐一会儿就行  -好
- I just need to sit down. - Sure.
我给您拿杯水
I'll get you some water.
再次感谢
Thanks again.
医生看上去不太好  芬奇
Our doctor doesn't look well, Finch.
手心出汗  流鼻血  希望我们没来迟
Clammy hands, nosebleeds. Just hope we're not too late.
打扰一下  弗斯科警探吗
Excuse me, Detective Fusco?
我是内务部的索里亚诺警探
Detective Soriano from Internal Affairs.
我们得聊聊
We need to talk.
-没什么聊的  -恐怕有的
- No, we don't. - I'm afraid we do.
事关斯蒂尔斯警探的失踪
It's regarding the disappearance of Detective Stills.
我们得没收
And we're gonna have to ask
你的警徽和配枪
for your badge and your service weapon.
这是怎么回事  弗斯科
What's this about, Fusco?
和你没关系  卡特
This don't concern you, Carter.
没关系
No?
我是你的搭档  我认为有关系
I'm your partner. I think it does.
和卡尔被杀案有关吗
This got something to do with Cal's murder?
没有
No.
告诉我  莱奈尔
Talk to me, Lionel.
为什么内务部突然盯上你了
Why is IAB all of a sudden putting the screws to you?
我曾经想告诉你
You know, I tried to come to you.
就在这间屋子里
In this very room.
告诉你我过去犯下的错误
To tell you about past mistakes I've made.
但你不想听
But you didn't want to hear it.
现在我在听
I'm listening now.
自食恶果罢了
Just chickens coming home to roost.
我身边的人都会倒霉  卡特
Bad things happen to people around me, Carter,
你还是离开吧
so you should get out of here.
这事儿没完
We're not done here.
芬奇  需要什么
Finch, what do you need?
节哀顺便  警探
I'm sorry for your loss, Detective.
谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
只是不明白
Just don't understand,
你掌握那么多资讯
with all the information you get,
这次我们为什么无法及时阻止
how we couldn't stop this in time.
这个问题也令我深受困扰
It's a question that troubles me as well.
我也希望能找到答案
I only wish I had an adequate answer.
我知道现在不是时候  不过
And I know this is not the best time, but--
你和约翰需要帮助
You and John need some help.
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
卡尔死了  弗斯科在被内务部调查
Cal is dead, and Fusco's being investigated by IAB.
我知道你很难受
I understand that you're upset,
但有名医生危在旦夕
but we have a doctor in peril.
我只需要你查几个名字
I just need you to check on a few names.
不行  不行
No. No.
这次  你得给我办点事了
This time, you're gonna do something for me.
好吧  警探  需要我做什么
Okay, Detective, what can I do for you?
你那克隆手机的手段
You know that phone cloning thing you do?
轮到我了
My turn.
喂
Hello?
感谢你的出席
Thanks for showing up.
我想这总好过你上周的那招
I guess it was better than that stunt you pulled last week,
泼红漆
throwing the red paint.
抱歉  爸爸  但民众有权利知道
Sorry, dad, but people have the right to know
医学院用动物来进行研究
the medical school uses animals for research.
听起来尼尔森和女儿之间有些问题
Sounds like Nelson has some issues with his daughter.
你也有权利知道  这所大学
And you have the right to know that this university
提供的薪水供了你的衣食住行
paid for your food, clothing, and the roof over your head
整整二十二年  更别提还供了你的学费
for the past 22 years, not to mention your tuition.
抱歉让你失望了  爸爸
Sorry if I disappointed you, dad.
该死  莫莉  这不是重点
Damn it, Molly, that's not the point.
我得挂电话了
I have to go.
我们以后再聊
We'll talk about this later.
医生刚刚吐血了
The doctor just vomited blood.
尼尔森有大麻烦了  我进去了
Nelson's in serious trouble. I'm going in.
911报警电话  有什么情况
911, what is your emergency?
我是理查德・尼尔森医生
Hi, this is Dr. Richard Nelson.
我想我可能是服入了有毒物质
I think I may have ingested something toxic.
-先生  您是医生吗  -是
- Sir, you're a doctor? - Yes.
我想可能是有人想杀我
I think someone may have tried to kill me.
你看上去需要帮助
You look like you need some help.
你
You!
我见过你  在招待会上
I know you from the reception.
-离我远点  -等等  医生
- Get away from me! - Wait, Doc--
-你是谁  -别
- Who are you? - No--
-纽约警察  谁打911报警  -我
- NYPD! Who called 911? - Me.
我报的  我要报告一起谋杀
I called it in. I want to report a murder.
谋杀  说什么呢  兄弟
Murder? What are you talking about, buddy?
-谁被谋杀了  -我
- Who was murdered? - Me!
有人给我下了毒
Someone poisoned me!
芬奇  情况急转直下
Finch, things just went completely sideways.
从他的症状看来  我们已经来迟了
And judging by his symptoms, we're already too late.
我们收到了一起旧案的新线索
We've received some new information on an old case.
你和吉米・斯蒂尔斯曾在51局共事吗
You and Jimmy stills worked together in the 51st?
是啊  还有很多别的警察
Yeah. So did a lot of other cops.
但你俩走的很近吧
But you two were close?
我是不会这么说的
I don't know if I'd put it that way.
那你怎么说
And how would you put it?
我们开始一起巡逻出警
We walked a beat together coming up.
后来他去了缉毒组  我去了凶案组
He went to Narcotics. I went to Homicide.
就这样
That's the long and short of it.
要打烊了
Last call!
奥尼尔  奥莱利  奥啥玩意儿
Hey, O'Neill-- O'reilly, O'whatever the hell your name is,
来杯酒
give us a drink.
不行  别喝了
No. You're done.
走吧  该回家了  哥们
Come on, it's time to hit the bricks, buddy.
说什么呢  还有5分钟呢
What are you talking about? We still got five minutes left.
放松  哥们
Easy there, big dog.
今晚喝得够多了
That's enough for one night.
回家吧
Let's get you home.
回不去了
I can't go home.
她把我赶出来了
She threw me out.
工作嘛
Comes with the job.
警察妻子嘛  她会回心转意的
Cop's wife. She'll come around.
这次不一样
Not this time.
她找律师给我发函了
She had a lawyer drop papers on me.
真的吗
Serious?
很遗憾
Sorry to hear about that.
吉米  她
Yeah, Jimmy, she--
她要儿子的完全监护权
she wants full custody of my son.
走吧  莱奈尔
Come on, Lionel.
回家  今晚住我家
You come home. You stay at my place tonight.
孩子们肯定乐意明早一起床
The kids will love waking up tomorrow morning,
直接扑倒你
jumping on your head.
我叫维拉做点薄煎饼
I'll have Vera cook up some hotcakes,
香蕉巧克力的
banana-chocolate chip.
加点阿司匹林
Throw some aspirin in the batter.
行吧  兄弟
Okay, amigo?
这样好吗
You sure it's okay?
朋友嘛  对不对
What are friends for?
走吧
Let's go.
我在重走医生刚才的路
I'm retracing the doctor's steps,
现在已经检测到了
and I'm already detecting
低剂量的阿尔法粒子发射  里瑟先生
low-level alpha particle emissions, Mr. Reese.
不太妙
Not good.
阿尔法粒子辐射
Alpha particle radiation.
是钋
It's polonium.
钋
Polonium?
经常被用来制造复杂的高精尖设备
Sometimes used to make complex tools in scientific equipment.
他是在实验室接触到的吗
Do you think he was exposed in the lab?
不  口服才会致命
No, it's only lethal if ingested
一小时内得不到救治就会死
and you don't get treated within the first hour.
整个区域都有污染
Well, the area's contaminated,
但并不像是源头
but it doesn't appear to be the point of origin.
尼尔森怎么样
What's Nelson's condition?
马上就知道了
I'm about to find out.
你  不  你是那服务员
You. No, you're that waiter.
这事跟你有关
You had something to do with this.
我不是服务员  是来帮你的
I'm not a waiter. I'm here to help you.
但你在招待会上
But you were at the reception.
你往酒里放东西了
You slipped something into my drink.
不  我没有  是别人
No, I didn't, but someone else did.
我是想救你
I was supposed to save you,
但是来迟了
but I was too late.
你服下去了钋  医生
You've ingested polonium, Doctor.
就要死了
You're dying.
真是疯了  怎么  你是谁
This is insane. How do--who are you?
鼻血  黄疸  脱发
Nosebleeds, jaundice, hair falling out.
是辐射中毒
It's radiation poisoning.
我知道辐射对人体的影响
I'm aware how radiation affects the body,
但你怎么知道的
but how do you know all this?
你几个小时前中的毒
You were poisoned a few hours ago,
也就是说  24小时之内
which means, in less than 24 hours,
你就会死
you will be dead.
抱歉  医生
I'm sorry, Doctor.
我  我不明白
I-I don't understand.
怎么
How--
谁会要我死
Who would want me dead?
你应该比我清楚
You would know better than I.
现在你可以躺在床上坐以待毙
Look, you can stay there and die in that bed,
或者跟我出去找到那个害死你的混蛋
or you can get up and help me find the bastard who murdered you.
时间不多了  医生
Clock's ticking, Doc.
是谁  我要知道
Who was it? I need to know.
首先解决私事
First we need to get your affairs in order.
你说得对  我要见我女儿
You're right. I need to see my daughter.
感谢你们的关注  感谢大家
Thank you for your interest. Thanks, guys.
-希望你能帮助我们  -莫莉  莫莉
- Hope you can make it to our benefit. - Molly? Molly?
能跟你说句话吗
Can I have a word with you?
她不想跟你说话
She doesn't want to talk to you.
让我来处理  好吗
I can handle it, okay?
大老远跑来骂我吗
Came all the way down here just to chew me out, huh?
还以为你要飞到什么地方参加研讨会呢
Thought you were jetting off to some seminar or something.
不  莫莉  我不是来吵架的
No, Molly, I didn't come here to argue.
我只想看看你好不好
I just came to see if you were okay.
真的吗
Really?
是啊  你妈妈说你要拍什么纪录片
Yeah, your mom said you're making some kind of documentary.
需要帮忙吗  需要钱或者别的吗
Do you need any help? Do you need money or anything?
你还好吗
Are you feeling okay?
脸色有点苍白
You look a little pale.
没事  我挺好  挺好
No, I'm fine. I'm fine.
我  我就是想来说一下
I-I just stopped by to say,
我很抱歉
I'm sorry for...
没有多花时间陪着你
not being more involved.
怎么  你指在我的生活中陪我  还是
What, like, in my life, or--
也许这是个错误  我不知道
Well, maybe this was a mistake, I don't know.
-我就是想  -你来干什么  爸爸
- I just wish-- - Why are you here, dad?
我知道我一直没陪伴你
Look, I know that I haven't been more available
总是工作为重
and putting my work first.
可能你妈妈也是因此离开的
That's probably why your mother left.
妈妈离开是因为你出轨
Mom left because you cheated on her.
我的又一错误
Another mistake.
但有个女儿不是错误
But the one that I didn't make was having a daughter.
今天早些时候  人们向我祝贺
Earlier today when people were congratulating me
我所取得的成就
about my accomplishments,
我在想的是
I-I was thinking that the thing
我最引以为豪的  是你
that I'm most proud of is you.
我就想说这些
That's all I came to say.
我明天打给你  爸爸
I'll call you tomorrow, dad.
当然  好的
Yeah, sure. Good.
我很期待
I would like that.
一开始  我想不清楚
At first, I couldn't figure it out.
斯蒂尔斯和阿扎雷洛在缉毒组工作
Stills and Azarello working Narcotics,
杀死毒贩  偷走藏毒
bumping dealers, stealing their stash.
复制手机
强制配对
约瑟夫・索里亚诺
完成
想着他们早晚会失手
Figured eventually they'd slip.
然后我灵光一现
Then it hit me.
他们里边安排了人  以防万一
They had a man on the inside, in case they made a mistake.
我听不懂
I don't follow.
他们需要在凶案组有内线
They needed somebody in Homicide.
你在51局的老朋友阿扎雷洛
Your old pal Azarello from the 51st,
他向我们招了
he clued us in.
告诉我  你们的团伙是怎么运行的
So tell me, how did your crew operate?
按部就班
Like clockwork.
先是斯蒂尔斯  他发现目标
First Stills, he got the drop on a honey pot.
我去打探情况  确保安全
I'd scope it out, make sure it was still hot.
然后开工
You know, then we'd roll up,
亮出警徽  抢走钱财毒品
flash the silver, and help ourselves to the money and the dope.
要是出了差错
But if things went south,
就叫弗斯科来处理
that's when Fusco came in.
阿扎雷洛就是个满口胡诌的货
Azarello's a lying piece of crap.
细节决定成败  弗斯科
The devil's always in the details, Fusco.
-跟我说说第一次  -我一辈子都不会忘
- Tell me about the first time. - I'll never forget.
那是在皇后区一间老鼠肆虐的房间里
It was some rat-infested tenement over in Queens.
你叫我过来干什么
Why you gotta bring me down here?
直接上报就行了
You just gotta call it in.
拜托  莱奈尔  你知道事儿容易出问题
Come on, Lionel, you know how these things can go sideways.
只需要凶案组帮点小忙
Just need a little help from Homicide here.
天
Jeez.
我刚开始搬  这蠢货就要逃跑
As soon as I started lifting, this dumb bastard tried to run.
我别无选择  他们要坑死我
I mean, I had no choice. They're gonna have my nuts here.
冷静  不会有事的
Calm down. Everything's gonna be fine.
在床头柜里找到了那玩意儿
Found that piece in the nightstand.
我们得赶在内务部的人来之前考虑好对策
We gotta figure out all the angles before IAB shows up.
你想让我帮你掩护
You're asking me to cover this?
我要完蛋了
I'm gonna be screwed.
过来  有问题吗
Come here. What's the problem?
我以为我们之间能相互支持
I thought we had each other's back.
是的  但你的要求实在
Yeah, but what you're asking me here is--
你有难时  是谁陪着你
When you needed somebody, who was there for you?
是谁支持你
Who had your back?
看看这个人渣
Look at this scumbag.
没准儿还卖过K粉给小孩儿
Probably slings to kids K through eight.
-怎么说  -我不知道
- What do you say? - I don't know.
为了朋友
For a friend.
站在那边  对着墙开两枪  齐胸高
Stand over there, put two in the wall, chest high.
然后是来是往  不管怎样都是正当防卫
Then, coming or going, either way, it's self-defense.
要擦干净
And wipe it down.
就这样
That's it.
谢了  莱奈尔
Thanks, Lionel.
瞧瞧这是哪阵风吹的
Look what the cat dragged in.
我最爱的逮捕警官
My favorite arresting officer.
气色不错  警探
Looking good, Detective.
别废话  阿扎雷洛
Skip it, Azarello.
你进监狱都一年多了
Look, you've been in jail for over a year.
为什么突然跟内务部说起弗斯科的事
Why all of a sudden you talking to IAB about Fusco?
也许我们是有规则的  警探
Maybe we got a code, Detective.
也许弗斯科违反了规则
Maybe Fusco violated it.
也许问题是你为什么现在才问起
Maybe the question should be why you're just now bringing up
你搭档的过去
your partner's past?
那真是绚丽多彩
It's pretty colorful.
我还以为弗斯科掌握了你的艳照啥的
I thought Fusco had some dirty pictures of you or something.
死了两名警察  失踪了两名
Two dead cops. Two missing.
这是HR的回归之作吗
Is this HR's idea of a comeback?
秘密很难埋藏
Secrets are hard to bury.
有时
And sometimes...
尸体总会露出来
bodies have a way of showing up.
我告诉你
Tell you what.
你帮我的忙  我会跟地检官谈谈
You help me out, I'll talk to the DA.
也许可以帮你因行为良好减刑
Maybe he shaves some time off for good behavior, huh?
你笑起来很好看  知道吗
You got a nice smile, you know that?
但现在想交易已经迟了  警探
But you're a little late to the deal-making party, Detective.
失陪了  我和袜子有个约会
If you'll excuse me, I got a date with a sock.
里克岛监狱之行收获如何  警探
How did it go at Rikers, Detective?
不怎么样  不过你要查的人  我倒是有发现
Not so good, but I did find something on one of your names.
那个资产经理  布兰登・博伊德
The asset manager, Brandon Boyd.
他是一家对冲基金的操盘手
He's a trader at a hedge fund.
VAC资本  我知道
VAC Capital, I'm aware.
你知道他们正在被证监会调查吗
Are you aware they're under SEC investigation?
内幕交易
Insider trading.
就在他们抛售了某家大型制药集团的股票之后
After they dumped some big pharmaceutical stock.
我猜猜  菲利亚制药
Let me guess. Philia Pharmaceuticals.
我在证监会的联系人认为
My contact at the SEC thinks
VAC资本
文森特・科克伦
创办人及执行总裁
他们得到了某个药物试验的消息
they got a tip on some drug trial.
这个有用吗
Does that help?
不幸的是  有用
Unfortunately, yes, it does.
-听说过VAC资本吗  -当然
- Ever heard of VAC Capital? - Yeah, sure.
他们管理我的资金
They manage my money.
他们正在被证监会调查内幕交易
They under SEC investigation for insider trading.
内幕交易  关于什么
Insider trading? On what?
你告诉过布兰登・博伊德有项药物试验即将失败吗
Did you tell Brandon Boyd that a drug trial was about to fail?
什么  我不知道  可能在俱乐部提过
What? I don't know. Maybe at the club.
他转头就利用这个消息
He turned around and used that information
做空菲利亚的股票
to bet against Philia stock,
赚了五亿
made $500 million.
王八蛋  五个亿
Son of a bitch. $1/2 billion dollars?
因为你的消息
Off your tip.
是你走漏的风声  医生
You're the leak, Doc.
正在被调查吗
There's an investigation?
他们还未找到内线
They don't know the insider yet.
我猜VAC资本打算维持住这一点
I'm guessing VAC Capital plans to keep it that way.
他们就想杀我
Instead they killed me?
你是包袱  你必须死
You're the liability. You had to go.
我是医生
I'm a doctor.
人们总是向我咨询  问我建议
People ask me things all the time, advice.
那种药物啊  这种食谱啊
You know, that drug and this diet and--
这都是借口
It's just an excuse.
我做错了
What I did was wrong,
现在我要死了
and now I'm a dead man.
都是因为我大嘴巴
All because I couldn't keep my mouth shut.
你是犯了错
You made a mistake.
那不意味着你该死
That doesn't mean you deserve to die.
你说得对
You're right.
我得找博伊德谈谈
I need to talk to Boyd.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese,
我想毒源已经找到了
I believe I've located the origin of the poisoning.
典礼讲台上的水被下了毒
It came from water placed on the podium at his ceremony.
当时的服务员只有两人
There were only two people on that service staff.
我和一位女服务员
Me and a waitress.
我想我知道她的雇主是谁
And I think I know who hired her.
该去找那名操盘手了
Time to go track down a trader.
-票  先生  -马上
- Ticket, Sir. - Right away.
好  查出持股份额后给我打电话
All right, so call me about the hold on those shares.
还有那个巴西性感模特的电话号码
And the number of that hot Brazilian model, huh?
回见  老板
Later, boss.
你的车  先生
Your car, Sir.
要小费[建议]吗
You want a tip?
没签婚前协议千万别结婚
Never get hitched without a prenup.
有个更好的建议
Here's a better one.
千万别上陌生人的车
Don't get in the car with strangers.
尼尔森医生  这是怎么回事
Dr. Nelson. What's going on here?
我的时间所剩无几了
I don't have a lot of time.
如果你回答错误就会跟我一样
And neither do you, if you answer me wrong.
你在俱乐部认识我
You met me at the club,
你拉我成了你的客户
you took me on as a client,
你装作是我朋友
and you pretended to be my friend.
我告诉了你那个药物试验
And I told you about a drug trial,
而你回过头来  捅了我一刀
and you turned around, and you burned me!
等下  我是操盘手
Wait a sec. I am a trader.
这是我的工作  操盘交易
That's all I do. I trade.
是的  你引发了证监会的调查
Yeah, and you triggered an SEC investigation.
在他们找到我之前  你给我下了毒
And before they found me, you poisoned me.
什么
What?
各位
Guys.
我对此毫不知情
I don't know anything about that.
-不知情吗  -你赶快停车
- No, huh? - Look, you should really just pull over now--
慢着  你不明白
Hold on. You don't understand.
老板分分钟盯着我
The boss is on my ass, 24/7.
你要么搞到"黑幕"  要么滚蛋
Either you get black edge, or you're out.
"黑幕"
Black edge?
就是内部消息  无人知晓的  确定无疑的
Inside information that no one else has, that's beyond doubt.
我们的钱全押在那药上
We were all-in on that drug,
我得找到与试验相关的人
but I needed to find someone on the trial.
要么搞到"黑幕"赚到大钱
Either you get that edge and turn big profits,
要么[星战角色]黑武士爆你蛋蛋
or Lord Vader cuts your balls off.
你就是为此接近我的吗
So that's why you recruited me?
我得占这便宜  而你想加入大型对冲基金
I needed that advantage, and you wanted in to a big hedge fund.
但我发誓这事跟我没关系
But I swear I had nothing to do with--
但你今天参加典礼了
But you were at the ceremony today.
对  我老板要求我定期去
Yeah, boss man said to go about my regular schedule.
你老板是指文森特・科克伦吗
By "boss man", you mean Vincent Cochran?
我已经说得够多了
Look, I've said enough already.
是的  文森特・科克伦
Yes! Vincent Cochran.
-你跟他提过我  -我不说不行
- And you told him about me? - I had to.
我们被调查  他询问我们是否已暴露
We got investigated. He asked if we'd been exposed.
-他说他会处理的  -科克伦现在在哪
- Said he'd take care of it. - Where's Cochran now?
你似乎没明白
You don't seem to understand.
你可不想惹上他
This is not a man you want to cross.
我告诉过你我视力下降得很厉害吗
Have I told you that my eyesight is failing?
好吧  度假屋
Okay! The lodge!
温德克赖斯特  州北
The Windcrest! Upstate!
我得跟卡特说句话
I need to talk to Carter.
我的孩子在等人接去训练
I need to have my kid picked up for practice.
先回答几个问题再说
As soon as you answer a few questions.
知道吗  弗斯科  不久前
You know, Fusco, it wasn't long ago
我也是便衣警探
that I was a plain clothes detective.
-真的吗  -真的
- No kidding. - No kidding.
但你知道你我之间的不同之处吗
But you know what the difference is between me and you?
-什么  -我没杀过人
- What's that? - I never murdered people.
我知道你不止为那帮家伙掩护
See, I know you weren't just covering for those guys.
你就是其中之一
You were one of them.
一旦进去  就别想回头
Once you get a taste of that, there's no looking back.
弗斯科  快进来
Fusco, get in here.
-搞什么名堂  -弗斯科  怎么啦
- Oh, for crying out loud. - Fusco, what's wrong?
一点血腥味都受不了吗
Can't stand the sight of a little blood?
别闹了  他好着呢
Hey, knock it off. He's good.
你拿一袋  这里多得是
Grab a bag. We got a big haul here.
不了  谢了  都是你们的
No, thanks. This is all you guys.
我可不想参与
I don't want any part of this.
现在为时已晚了  不是吗
It's a little late for that, ain't it?
小心
Look out!
看到没  就知道你靠得住
You see there? I knew you were solid.
欢迎加入  莱奈尔
Welcome to the crew, Lionel.
好了  我们走
All right, let's get out of here.
快点  我们走
Come on. Let's go.
阿扎雷洛供出你了
Azarello flipped on you.
我们本以为斯蒂尔斯逃往了[南美]伯利兹
We thought Stills was halfway to Belize,
现在我们知道了并非如此
but now we know different.
你不得不除掉他
You got rid of him because you had to.
你只凭一名黑警的谎言
All you got is lies from a dirty cop.
在法庭上站不住脚
It'll never hold up in court.
你知道什么才能在法庭上站住脚吗
Well, you know what will hold up in court?
证据
Evidence.
当黑警们想要
You see, when dirty cops want
抹掉犯罪现场的DNA时
to eliminate DNA from a crime scene,
他们会使用漂白水
they use bleach.
但漂白水会有残留
But bleach stains things.
比如残留在车辆的地毯上  后备箱里
Like the carpet and the trunk of the vehicle
就是你在斯蒂尔斯失踪当天登记开出的车
that you signed out on the day that Stills disappeared.
不知道你在说什么
No idea what you're talking about.
你的电话记录
Your cell phone records.
就在斯蒂尔斯失踪当晚
You made a call from Oyster bay to your home
你从牡蛎湾打了一个电话回家
the very night that Stills went missing.
星期四半夜两点你为何会在牡蛎湾
Any reason you were in Oyster bay at 2:00 am on a Thursday?
考虑退休后去那里
Thinking about retiring out there.
想去看看地
Wanted to look at some land.
你还采集了土样
You take soil samples?
觉醒吧  朋友
Domain awareness, my friend.
卫星  改变了这个世界
Satellites, they're changing the world.
你挑个时间地点
You pick a time and place,
我们能给你发张青蛙屁股毛的照片
we send you a photo of the ass hairs on a frog,
或者这个  牡蛎湾被翻过的地
or in this case, disturbed plots of earth in Oyster bay.
是这四个中的哪一块  警探
Which of the four is it, Detective?
我有两打人员正在集结铲子
I got two dozen unis gathering shovels,
挖土机和寻尸犬
a backhoe, and cadaver dogs.
天一亮  我们就要去寻宝了
Come sunup, we're gonna go on a little treasure hunt.
别难为自己了
Make it easy on yourself.
直接说你把斯蒂尔斯埋在哪里了
Just tell me where you buried Stills.
我知道你杀死了他
I know you killed him,
就像杀死其他底层混混一样
just like those lowlifes.
你是个黑警  明天一早
You're a dirty cop, and come morning,
我就会挖出你的罪恶
I'm gonna dig up your sins.
想谈谈吗
You wanted to talk?
那个
So...
你之前问我的那些问题
the questions you asked me earlier--
我没有回答的那些
the ones I didn't answer.
我没有杀斯蒂尔斯
I didn't kill Stills,
但我还是会背上这罪名
but I'm gonna go down for it just the same.
但我活该  因为
But I deserve it because of--
因为
Because?
因为我做过别的坏事
Because of the other bad things I did.
我在51局工作时
You see, back at the 51st--
得  等等  什么叫"别的坏事"
All right, wait, what do you mean, "the other bad things"?
最初  我
See, at-- at first, I...
我以为我算替天行道  知道吗
I thought I was helping to clean up the streets, you know?
谁会在乎一个底层毒贩子的毒品钱呢
Who's gonna miss some drug money from a lowlife dealer?
接着演变成谁会在乎一个毒贩子呢
Then it became who's gonna miss the dealer?
我和  我和斯蒂尔斯  我们是朋友
Me and... me and Stills, we were friends.
他就像兄弟一样陪我  知道吗
He was there for me like a brother, you know?
支持我
He had my back.
后来
And then...
后来就发现自己陷入一种境地
then you find yourself in a situation,
一种不应该置身其中的不良境地
a bad situation that you shouldn't be in.
我杀过人  卡特
I killed people, Carter.
我曾是黑警
I was a dirty cop.
但  自从遇到你和我们的朋友
But, since I met you and our friends,
一切都变了
that's all changed.
我不再是过去的我了
I'm not that guy anymore.
你总跟我说  如果
You always told me that if--
如果我的过去又阴魂不散
that if my past came back around,
你不会替我掩护  我也不会要求你
you wouldn't cover for me, and I'm not asking you to.
我只希望你理解
I just need you to understand--
停下
Stop.
我不能
I can't.
我不想再听下去了
I don't want to hear any more.
我不认识你了  莱奈尔
I don't know who you are, Lionel.
医生  坚持住
Doc, stay with me.
就想当面见见杀我的那个混蛋
Just wanted to look the bastard who killed me in the face.
-不要放弃  -没事的
- Don't give up yet. - It's okay.
这是报应
It's time to face the consequences.
我们都会犯错
We all make mistakes.
我
I--
天  他是死了吗
Man, hey, did he just die?
天  他死了吗
Oh, man, is he dead?
闭嘴  否则下一个轮到你
Shut up, or you're next.
上帝啊  你不会是想
Oh, my God, you're not gonna--
拜托  拜托  拜托
Come on. Come on. Come on.
你还不能死
You can't die yet.
我们还有个任务要完成
We've got one more mission to finish.
来吧
Come on.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
你不能把我扔在这儿傻站着
Hey, you can't just leave me standing out here.
你说得对
You're right.
认出我了吗  科克伦先生
You recognize me, Mr. Cochran?
我该认出吗
Should I?
我是被你谋杀的人
I'm the man you murdered.
弗斯科的事你打算怎么做
What are you doing about Fusco?
目前  不做  在忙
At the moment, nothing. I'm busy.
我们一起经历了这么多
After all we've been through,
我还以为他是你的朋友
I thought he was your friend.
我一直以为他是你的搭档
I always thought he was your partner.
他跟我说了那些事之后就不是了
Not after what he just told me.
你知道他做过什么吗
Do you know what he's done?
他应该被关进监狱
He deserves to be behind bars.
卡特  可从来没人请我当道德指导
Listen, Carter, no one's ever looked at me as the moral benchmark.
我看这决定你必须自己做
I guess you'll have to make that call yourself.
我是警察  好吗  但那是弗斯科
I'm a cop, okay? But it's Fusco.
并没那么容易
It's not as simple as that.
我一直以为对你来说很容易
I always thought it was in your book.
一朝是黑警  永远是黑警  是吧
Once a dirty cop, always a dirty cop, right?
失陪一下
You'll have to excuse me.
我得继续工作了
I have to get back to work.
你知道钋会对人体造成什么影响
You know what polonium does to the human body,
科克伦先生
Mr. Cochran?
我觉得你准备告诉我了
I have a feeling you're about to tell me.
钋一进入血液中
Once it enters the bloodstream,
就马上开始摧毁免疫系统
it immediately starts to break down the immune system.
渗入骨髓之中
It seeps into the bone marrow,
使你的身体无法抵挡自身的细菌
so your body can no longer fend off its own bacteria,
细菌就开始从内部吞噬你
which starts to eat you from the inside out.
攻击你的DNA
It attacks your DNA,
关闭你的内脏功能
shuts down your internal organs.
很快  不过我敢保证
It's fairly rapid, but I assure you,
异常痛苦
it's very painful.
真惊讶你还在这里
Amazing you're still here.
最后的二十四小时如同身临地狱
The last 24 hours have been a living hell.
真是邪恶的杀人方式
It's a truly diabolical way of killing someone.
不过我只是医生
But then I'm just a doctor.
对抗不了精明世故的
I'm no match for a shrewd,
国际对冲基金亿万富豪
international hedge fund billionaire.
也许你太低估自己了
Perhaps you sell yourself short.
不  我现在明白了
Oh, no, I get it now.
你和你的公司  你们真正感兴趣的不是
You and your firm, you're not really interested
医学药物和治愈疾病
in medicinal drugs or curing disease.
你只想赚钱
You're just a man who makes money,
不择手段啊
even if you have to cheat, hmm?
我是投资者  我交易股票
I'm an investor. I trade stocks.
但如果我发现自己挑了垃圾股
But if I know I picked a loser,
就必须抛了
I have to dump it.
无论如何  我总是赢
Either way, I always win.
我做过好事  做过坏事
I've done some good things, some bad.
我曾毁了我的生活  我的名誉
I managed to ruin my life, my reputation.
但我并不该死
But I don't deserve to die.
证监会将会扳倒你的公司
And the SEC will bring your firm down.
不幸的是  医生
Unfortunately, Doctor,
证监会的调查将会伴你死去
the SEC investigation will die with you.
我想你说的是伴我们俩
I think you mean us.
你鼻子在流血
Your nose is bleeding.
你有九十亿
You have $9 billion,
却只有二十四小时来花了
but you only have 24 hours to spend it.
希望你明智投资
I hope you invest it wisely.
弃尸的好地方
Nice place to dump a body.
不过一点小雪挡不住警犬
But a little snow won't keep the dogs from finding it.
来吧  到结局了
Let's go. End of the line.
综合说来  身为一名警察
You know, at the end of the day, as a cop,
一般都处于这么一种境地
you're the sum of two sides of the ledger.
有人恨不得你完蛋
The people who want to see you go down
有人根本不鸟你
and the people who don't give a crap about you.
而现在  弗斯科  我认为根本没人鸟你
Now, Fusco, I don't think anyone gives a crap about you.
警探  这边
Detective, up this way.
来吧  我们走
Come on. Let's go.
别担心  亲爱的
Don't worry, honey.
会有其他人的  相信我
There'll be other guys. Trust me.
我也爱你  甜心
I love you too, sweetheart.
拜
Good-bye.
62年珍藏版  你的最爱
'62 limited edition. Your favorite.
混蛋玩意儿
Cheeky bastard.
谢谢你
And thank you.
谢什么
For what?
谢谢你给我这最后一杯[最后机会]
For giving me another shot.
还有这一切
At all this.
尼尔森医生死了  芬奇
We lost Dr. Nelson, Finch.
他是个好人
He was a good man.
我们来迟了  来不及救他
We arrived too late to save him.
似乎"来迟"得太多了
Seems to be a common occurrence of late.
先是舍曼斯基  后是比彻  现在又是尼尔森医生
First Szymanski, then Beecher, now Dr. Nelson.
机器出问题了吗  芬奇
Is something wrong with the machine, Finch?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们还错过了谁呢
Then who else are we missing?
早晚的事儿了  弗斯科
Just a matter of time now, Fusco.
你躺那里边  我拿把铲子如何
What do you say you lay down in this hole, I'll grab a shovel?
过去
Get up there.
索里亚诺警探
Detective Soriano.
该面对现实了  弗斯科
Time to face the truth, Fusco.
长官  警犬在这里示警了
Sir, the canine alerted right here,
土是松的
and the soil was loose.
这里曾经埋尸  警探  但是
There was a body here, Detective, but--
有人挪走了
Somebody moved it.
你当是开玩笑吗
You think this is some kind of joke?
我知道是你杀了斯蒂尔斯  你个王八蛋
I know you killed Stills, you son of a bitch.
你把尸体怎么着了
What'd you do with the body?
去你妈的
Screw you.
这事儿没完  弗斯科
This ain't over, Fusco.
我知道你是黑警
I know you're a dirty cop.
你错了
You're wrong about that.
我要拿回我的配枪和警徽
And I'll take my gun and shield back now.
弗斯科有消息吗
Any word on Fusco?
脱身了  暂时
Off the hook for now.
我监狱里那位棋友说
My chess partner in prison says
阿扎雷洛改变心意  撤回供词了
Azarello had a change of heart and recanted.
将军
Checkmate.
真好
Good to hear.
我之前提过的那场风暴
That storm on the horizon that I mentioned,
恐怕已经到来了
I'm afraid it's arrived.
病毒状态
芬奇  小熊呢
Finch, where's Bear?
是了  这事我们也得讨论一下
Oh, yes, that's the other matter that we need to discuss.
正好需要人帮把手
Need some fresh eyes on a lead I'm running.
能帮我看下吗
You mind giving it a look?
我回头再跟你说说进度
And I'll catch up with you later.
昨晚太累了
I had a long night.
当然  没问题
Sure, no problem.
信号损坏
致命错误
修正操作  试探离线
威胁系统
首要操作
关闭系统